Michael Hunt

investigations.

Physics PhD and aspiring data scientist

mbh038@gmail.com | ♠ mbh038 | ♥ Michael Hunt

Currently

I have worked as a lecturer in the HE in FE sector for 19 years, having previously been a research physicist in Switzerland and France for 6 years. I have written, managed and delivered a number of HE courses up to Masters level, including a BSc Renewable Energy and Carbon Management. In the last two years, in an effort to develop my data modelling and analysis skills, I have successfully completed many (>25) MOOCs in statistical analysis, machine learning, big data and more, mainly using R, and Python but also Matlab, MS Azure and other tools. I have so far used these new skills to carry out market research, to model heat flows in old buildings, to simulate wind speed and solar variation and to model a pumped storage energy solution for a local town. The heat flow work was part of a long running collaboration with conservation officers within Cornwall Council, funded by a Townscape Heritage Initiative lottery money. It was published last year and presented at an international conference (EECHB 2016). I am now embarking on a machine learning/IoT project to develop a biologger and software to determine the state of movement of farm animals from accelerometer data alone.

Employment

1998–	Cornwall College HE lecturer, course manager and curriculum area manager.
1997-1998	CNRS Lab. Louis Neel OXSEN Research Fellow, developing magnetic transistors.
1996-1997	Physics Department, University of Zuerich Oxygen isotope investigations of Hi Tc superconductors using
	dilatometry.
1995–1996	ABB Applied Physics Group, Corporate Research Centre, Baden Daettwil Dilatometric studies of 1 MW Hi Tc
	superconducting current limiter.
1995–1996	Solid State Physics Lab., ETH Zuerich Low temperature studies of transport properties in metals
1981–1982	Research Centre, British Gas, Solihull, UK Coding in FORTRAN and assembly to support gas dispersion

Education

1982-1985

1989–1992	University of Bristol PhD Physics
	"A de Haas-van Alphen Investigation of the heavy fermion superconductor CeCu2Si2"
	Supervisor: Mike Springford
1987-1988	University of Sussex MSc Physics by Research
	"A de Haas-van Alphen investigation of lithium" (Distinction)

University of Cambridge BA Natural Science (Physics)

Presentations

2016 EECHB: Life Cycle Analysis of Historic Buildings in Cornwall(*EECHB*, Brussels, Belgium)

Publications

I have 24 publications in peer reviewed journals, almost all dating from my years as a post-grad and post-doc 1989-1998. See my profiles on Research Gate or Google Scholar for listings of these. One paper was published in Nature and has over 300 citations. More recently (2016) I presented work at an international conference (EECHB, 2016) on energy efficiency in historic buildings. This was an analysis carried out using R of heat flow through thick, solid walls.

Certifications

Many online courses in 2015-2016. The code written for most of these can be found in repos on my GitHub page. Most courses required between 20 and 100 hours of work over 4 - 8 weeks.

Technical skills					

Awards

Platform	Course	Institution	Grade
Coursera	The Data Scientist's Toolbox	JHU	100%
Coursera	R Programming	JHU	100%
Coursera	Getting and Cleaning Data	JHU	100%
Courgera	Exploratory Data Analysis	JHU	100%
Coursera	Reproducible Research	JHU	100%
	Statistical Inference	JHU	100%
	Regression Models	JHU	100%
Coursera	Practical Machine Learning	JHU	100%
Coursera	Developing Data Products	JHU	100%
Coureerax	Data Analysis and Statistical Inference	Duke	99%
edX Machin	e learning tics Edge	MITx	96%
Futurel earn	Big Data	U. Warwick	100%
	Introduction to Big Data	U. San Diego	100%
Coursera	Hadoop Platform and Application Framework	U. San Diego	100%
Coursera	Introduction to Big Data Analytics	U. San Diego	100%
Coursera	Programming for Everybody	U. Michigan	100%

2017

	Coursetaractions gatataloaises avith இதும்றை patterns and their potential associations with Michigan நடுமென்கள்			
	edX <i>challei</i>	ാള് കൂട്ടാള് പ്രത്യാൻ പ്രവ്യാധ്യാൻ പ്രവാധ വാധിക്ക് വിഷ്ട്ര വിഷ്ട്ര വാധിക്കുന്നു. വിഷ്ട്ര വാധിക്ക് വിഷ്ട്ര വാധിക്കുന്നു. വിഷ്ട്ര വാധിക്കുന്നു വാധിക്കാര് വാധിക്	MITx	98%
	edX	Introduction to Computational Thinking and Data Science	MITx	97%
	edX	Data Science and ML Essentials	Microsoft	93%
Interests	Lagonita	Statistical Learning	U. Stanford	88%
	edX _{Trail ru}	Machine Learning Inning - several Limes a week, most weeks.	U. Stanford	100%
	edX Projected top 50	Staffstics and R t Euler - 181 problems solved so far, using Python, C++, Mathematica, M	HarvardX atlab and R. H HarvardX	100% oming in on the UK 100%
	edX top 50	Statistical Inference and Modeling for High-throughput Experiments	HarvardX	98%
	edX	High-Dimensional Data Analysis	HarvardX	100%
Links	edX	Annotation and Analysis of Genomes and Genomic Assays	HarvardX	99%
LIIKS	edX	High-performance Computing for Reproducible Genomics	HarvardX	99%
	edX ≥ ema	^{ail} Case Studies in Functional Genomics	HarvardX	99%
	edX Gith	lubilobal Warming Science	HarvardX	100%
	edX y twit	^{te} Case Studies in Functional Genomics	MITx	100%
	Futur	hchaustes of Climate Change	U. Bergen	100%
	Coursel 200	glenafoodletion to programming with Matlab	Vanderbilt U.	100%

References

Available on request.